<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 22:43:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thor and Loki</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/projects/thor-loki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 22:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/projects/thor-loki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CUAUV was my first experience working on a relatively complex
robotics project, an underwater robot with a 50-person team
consisting of about 15 software team members. (I had competed in high
school robotics, but I was leading a relatively small 3-person team.)
The objective of CUAUV is
to produce a robot to compete in the international RoboSub
competition. As a team member, I developed an interest
in computer vision, researching topics such as graph-based image
segmentation to enable object detection invariant to lighting
conditions and visual egomotion in order to caculate velocity without
an expensive sonar sensor. I implemented simple proof-of-concept prototype
algorithms for both of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the competition takes in July, some team members opt to stay
on-campus over the summer to work on the robot. I opted to stay
during Summer 2016 as a sophomre. I worked extensively on computer vision algorithms
and high-level state machine and control logic to
to complete the &amp;ldquo;Torpedoes&amp;rdquo; task at RoboSub 2016. The task consisted of
identifing targets labeled with letters, removing a physical cover from a target,
and shooting plastic projectiles at targets with specified letters.
(Video and images are shown below.) I spent nearly all of my time
that summer writing computer vision code, testing and collecting logs in the pool,
and revising and re-desgining code as needed to account for new failure
modes, re-running against the collected log data, and finally
re-testing in the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a fantastic experience attending RoboSub 2016, speaking with
other teams about how they had approached the challenges and watching
my code manuver the vehicle around the obstacle course. I was super
excited when our team acheived third place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>